EMRE CAN YESILYURT

emre@yesilyurt.dev | emreyesilyurt.me | +90 532 063 4081 | Ankara/Turkey (Open to Relocate)

LinkedIn: yesilyurtemre | GitHub: emreyesilyurt | Medium: emreyesilyurt | Youtube: yesilyurtemre

Personal Profile

Versatile Data Engineer experienced in developing and deploying data pipelines on cloud platforms. Specializes in leveraging Large Language Models to automate processes. Dedicated to community building and knowledge sharing, with a strong focus on growing alongside communities.

Professional Experience

Data Engineer, EETech | July 2022 - Present | Boise, Idaho, United States (Remote)

- Developed **LLM based** product notification labeling system to inform clients about changed, discontinued, cross products with **fine tuned LLama3** model. Observed 35% more accuracy than manual labeling.
- Developed BigQuery **trend forecasting** pipeline with 97% accuracy using ARIMA_PLUS model to select the optimal product from cross products and choose the best purchase dates.
- Conducted feature extraction on categorical data, enhancing multivariate trend forecasting accuracy.
- Created a **custom scoring algorithm** using statistical methods to identify the most predictable time series across billions of time series, to provide clients with the reliable trend forecasts and predictable products.
- Ensured data quality assurance using Python and BigQuery.
- Developed **python standardization tool** to standardize categorical features from offline data sources

Data Science Intern, Data Glacier | Feb 2022 - May 2022 | Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, India (Remote)

- Conducted open exploratory data analysis notebooks using advanced libraries such as SciPy, Statsmodels, TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, scikit-learn, XGBoost, Seaborn and Plotly. These notebooks were shared within communities and personal GitHub profiles for knowledge sharing.

Volunteer Experience

Python Mentor, Global AI Hub | Jun 2022 - Aug 2022 | Istanbul, Turkey

- Collaborated with a team of mentors in a python bootcamp attended by over 1,500 participants.

Core Member, Global AI Hub | Mar 2022 - Present | Istanbul, Turkey

- Contributed to AI education initiatives and supported new members in their learning process.

Technical Writer, Machine Learning Turkiye | Apr 2020 - Present | Istanbul, Turkey

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Management Information Systems, Dokuz Eylul University | 2018 - 2022

Dissertation: Developed an interactive chatbot on GCP, currently in use at ybs.deu.edu.tr

Skills

Languages: Python, C, C++

Developer Tools: Version Control (Git), Google Cloud Platform, BigQuery ML, Azure, AWS, Looker, Linux, Anaconda

Data Science: Large Language Models, Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Natural Language Processing, Data Modelling